In a cavernous, dimly lit hold, a blocky, rust-orange mechanical figure slumps against a pillar among scattered crates and trailing cables. A green light flickers to life across its visor.
The ancient machine shifts its heavy head.
A figure frozen behind frosted glass.
In the center of a vast, circular chamber, the solitary robot rests beneath a ring of pale light. A nearby console projects a holographic planet.
A red engine failure warning flashes.
Zolya sleeps peacefully inside a frosted pod.
The pale light inside her pod flickers and dims.
Silent pods line the dark hall.
One by one, the faint lights on the pods extinguish, plunging the corridor into darkness.
The shadows swallow everything.
In the pitch black, the green slit of the robot's visor flares back to life.
Massive doors open at the far end of the corridor, carving a brilliant shaft of white light through the dusty air. It washes over the rows of cryo-pods, illuminating the solitary machine.
The robot stares into the blinding glare.
In a green-tinged nebula, a colossal, hollowed-out asteroid glows with internal golden fires. A sleek, ring-shaped vessel, the Argosy, emerges from the rocky remnants.
The ancient colony ship glides away from the glowing husk, charting a course toward the stars before fading into the vast, cosmic dark.